Guide to the Northern Pacific Railway Company Records 1870-1968
Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, The University of Montana--Missoula
- Branch Lines, Predecessors and Related Companies, 1881-1960; Subgroup 2; 60.75 linear feet and 18 oversize volumes
  - Gaylord and Ruby Valley Railway Company, 1897-1902; Series XXXIII; 1.0 linear feet
    The Gaylord and Ruby Valley Railway Company started a line from Renovo to Twin Bridges, Montana. The company was incorporated on March 29, 1897 and sold to the NPRR on February 28, 1899. Line construction was completed by the NPRR. This series consists entirely of general correspondence dealing with line construction, employment, building materials, subcontractor communications, rights of way inquiries, facility designs, and traffic summaries.
    - General Correspondence, Employment, 1897 - 1898 (Box-folder 326/1)
    - General Correspondence, Fencing and Cattleguards, 1897 - 1898 (Box-folder 326/2)
    - General Correspondence, Construction, 1897 - 1898 (Box-folder 326/3)
    - General Correspondence, Bids, 1897 - 1898 (Box-folder 326/4)
    - General Correspondence, Buildings, 1898 (Box-folder 326/5)
    - General Correspondence, Pass Books, 1897 - 1898 (Box-folder 326/6)
    - General Correspondence, Rights of Way, 1897-03 - 1897-11 (Box-folder 326/7)
    - General Correspondence, Rights of Way, 1897-11 - 1897-12 (Box-folder 326/8)
    - General Correspondence, Rights of Way, 1898 (Box-folder 326/9)
    - General Correspondence, Rights of Way, 1898 (Box-folder 326/10)
    - General Correspondence, Car Reports, 1901 (Box-folder 326/11)
    - General Correspondence, Track Laying and Ballasting, 1901 (Box-folder 326/12)
    - General Correspondence, Operation of Line, 1901 (Box-folder 326/13)
    - General Correspondence, Estimates, 1901 (Box-folder 326/14)
    - General Correspondence, Progress of Work, 1901 (Box-folder 326/15)
    - General Correspondence, Expense Accounts, 1901 - 1902 (Box-folder 326/16)
    - General Correspondence, 1897 - 1898 (Box-folder 326/17)
    - General Correspondence, 1901 - 1902 (Box-folder 326/18)
    - General Correspondence, Proposals and Bids, 1901 - 1902 (Box-folder 327/1)
    - General Correspondence, Location of Stations, Names and Facilities, 1901 - 1902 (Box-folder 327/2)
    - General Correspondence, Contracts, 1901 - 1902 (Box-folder 327/3)
    - General Correspondence, Requisitions, Invoices and Vouchers, 1901 - 1902 (Box-folder 327/4)
    - General Correspondence, Materials, 1897 (Box-folder 327/5)
    - General Correspondence, Materials, 1898 (Box-folder 327/6)
    - General Correspondence, Materials, 1901 (Box-folder 327/7)
    - General Correspondence, Materials, 1901 - 1902 (Box-folder 327/8)
    - General Correspondence, Location of Line, 1901 - 1902 (Box-folder 327/9)
    - General Correspondence, Water, 1901 (Box-folder 327/10)
    - General Correspondence, Grading, 1901 (Box-folder 327/11)
    - General Correspondence, Bridges, 1898 (Box-folder 327/12)
    - General Correspondence, Bridges, 1901 (Box-folder 327/13)
  - Grays Harbor and Columbia River Railway Company, 1901-1909; Series XXXIV; 0.25 linear feet
    The Grays Harbor and Columbia River Railway Company series is composed entirely of three bound outgoing construction correspondence volumes.
    - Outgoing Correspondence, J. Hoquiam, 1901-1902 (Box-volume 328/451)
    - Outgoing Correspondence, H.H. Edgerton, 1906-1907 (Box-volume 328/452)
    - Outgoing Correspondence, G.D. Ball, 1908-1909 (Box-volume 328/453)
  - Great Northern Railway Company, 1909; Series XXXV; 1 oversize volume
    The Great Northern Railway Company was originally the St. Paul, Minneapolis and Manitoba Railroad Company (incorporated May 23, 1879); the St. Paul and Pacific Railroad Company (incorporated March 10, 1862), and the Minneapolis and St. Cloud Railroad Company (incorporated March 1, 1956). Originally operating in Minnesota and the Midwest, the company completed its line from Duluth and St. Paul, Minnesota, to Everett and Seattle, Washington in 1893. This series contains one bound volume of cash transactions from the Vaughn Junction station.
    - Station Agent's Cash Book, Vaughn Junction, 1909 (Volume 454)
  - Green River and Northern Railroad Company, 1887-1891; Series XXXVI; 0.5 linear feet and 1 oversize volume
    The Green River and Northern Railroad Company was incorporated on September 22, 1890 and was sold to the NPRR on April 21, 1898. It was a branch line that joined the NPRR system at Palmer Junction in western Washington state. This series contains outgoing construction correspondence, voucher requests, materials from the Kangley Mine Branch, and supply reports.
    - Outgoing Correspondence, 1887 (Box-volume 329/455)
    - Outgoing Correspondence, William Gould and F. Bartlett, 1890 (Box-volume 329/456)
    - Outgoing Correspondence, 1890-1891 (Box-volume 329/457)
    - Vouchers, 1890 (Volume 458)
    - Index to v. 458, 1890-1891 (Box-volume 329/459)
    - Record of Vouchers, Kangley Mine Branch, 1889 (Box-volume 329/460)
    - Report on Material Received, 1890 (Box-volume 329/461)
  - Kootenai Valley Railroad Company, 1890; Series XXXVII; 1 bound volume
    The Kootenai Valley Railroad Company's main line ran from Bonners Ferry, Idaho, to Porthill, Idaho, on the Canadian border. The company was incorporated on October 19, 1898 and merged into the Great Northern Railway Company in 1913. This series contains one bound volume of outgoing correspondence from C.J. Hollingsworth, Assistant Engineer.
    - Outgoing Correspondence, C.J. Hollingsworth, 1890 (Box-volume 330/462)
  - Livingston-Gardner Branch, 1922-1960; Series XXXVIII; 0.25 linear feet
    The Livingston-Gardner Branch operated from Livingston to Gardner, Montana. This series contains general correspondence, construction records, and design blueprints generated by the Yellowstone National Park Branch of the NPRR.
    - General Correspondence, Park Branch, 1922-1960 (Box-folder 330/1)
    - General Correspondence, Park Branch, 1922-1960 (Box-folder 330/2)
    - Park Branch Blueprints, 1922-1960 (Box-folder 330/3)
    - Park Branch Blueprints, 1922-1960 (Box-folder 330/4)
  - Manitoba Southwestern Colonization Railway, 1881-1882; Series XXXIX; 1 folder
    The Manitoba Southwestern Colonization Railway series consists of one bound volume detailing supplies received.
    - Receipt of Materials, 1881 - 1882 (Box-volume 330/463)
  - Missoula and Bitter Root Valley Railroad Company, 1887-1888; Series XL; 1 partial reel of microfilm and 2 bound volumes
    The Missoula and Bitter Root Valley Railroad Company operated a line from Missoula to Grantsdale, Montana in 1888. That same year, it was incorporated into the Northern Pacific and Montana Railroad Company. This series consists of one partial reel of microfilm documenting a traffic contract between the M&BRVRR and the Northern Pacific Railway, one bound volume containing outgoing correspondence from C. F. Reardon, the M&BRVRR Assistant Engineer, and one bound volume of vouchers for purchases by railroad personnel.
    - Traffic Contract, 1887-06 (Microfilm 128(XL):1)
    - Outgoing Correspondence, C. F. Reardon, 1887 - 1888 (Box-volume 331/464)
    - Vouchers, C. F. Reardon, 1887 - 1888 (Box-volume 331/465)
  - Missouri River Railway Company, 1909-1912; Series XLI; 8.25 linear feet
    The Missouri River Railway Company built track from Glendive to Sidney, Montana, and from Cannon Ball to Stanton, North Dakota. The company was incorporated June 13, 1906, in North Dakota and was sold to the NPRR on June 20, 1914. This series contains construction correspondence, assest and supply records, expense reports, subcontractor documents, rights of way inquiries and property acquisitions, progress reports, supply inventories, facility documents, and personnel records. These materials constitute an unusually detailed and deep resource for studying economic patterns and land ownership histories for central eastern Montana.
    - Outgoing Correspondence, 1912-06 - 1912-11 (Box-volume 331/466)
    - Outgoing Correspondence, 1909-01 - 1910-06 (Box-volume 331/467)
    - Outgoing Correspondence, 1909-05 (Box-volume 331/468)
    - Outgoing Correspondence, 1909-04 (Box-volume 331/469)
    - Construction Expenses, 1909-06 - 1909-09 (Box-folder 332/1)
    - Construction Expenses, 1909-10 - 1910-01 (Box-folder 332/2)
    - Construction Expenses, 1910-02 - 1910-08 (Box-folder 332/3)
    - Construction Expenses, 1910-09 - 1910 - 10 (Box-folder 332/4)
    - Camp Expenses, Grading, 1909-07 - 1911-02 (Box-folder 332/5)
    - Expenses and Work, Pittsburgh Construction, 1910-01 - 1911-01 (Box-folder 332/6)
    - Expenses and Work, Pittsburgh Construction, 1911-09 - 1912-09 (Box-folder 332/7)
    - Expenses, Siems and Carey Company, 1911 - 1912 (Box-folder 333/1)
    - Expenses, Kerrick Construction, 1912-05 - 1912-10 (Box-folder 333/2)
    - Expenses, Wren and Greenough Company, 1909 - 1910 (Box-folder 333/3)
    - Return of Time Reports, 1911-08 - 1912-09 (Box-folder 334/1)
    - General Correspondence, 1909-05 - 1910-11 (Box-folder 334/2)
    - Rights of Way and Land Acquisitions, 1909-05 - 1909-07 (Box-folder 334/3)
    - Rights of Way and Land Acquisitions, 1909-08 - 1909-12 (Box-folder 334/4)
    - Rights of Way and Land Acquisitions, 1910-01 - 1910-12 (Box-folder 334/5)
    - Ballasting, 1909-07 - 1910-09 (Box-folder 335/1)
    - Track Laid, 1912-04 - 1912-06 (Box-folder 335/2)
    - Cars Underload and Demurrage, 1909-07 - 1910-10 (Box-folder 335/3)
    - Crossings, Fencing, and Road Changes, 1909-05 - 1910-12 (Box-folder 335/4)
    - Pipe, Culverts, and Iron for Bridges, 1909-05 -1910-12 (Box-folder 335/5)
    - Temporary Bridges and Reclamation, 1909-06 - 1910-10 (Box-folder 335/6)
    - Porter Brothers and Welch Contract, 1909-12 - 1910-09 (Box-folder 335/7)
    - Grading, 1909-05 - 1910-10 (Box-folder 335/8)
    - Linden Creek Flume, 1909-07 - 1909-10 (Box-folder 335/9)
    - Progress Reports, 1909 (Box-folder 336/1)
    - Progress Reports, 1910 (Box-folder 336/2)
    - Progress Profiles, 1909-06 - 1910-10 (Box-folder 336/3)
    - Employment Records, 1909-05 - 1910-07 (Box-folder 336/4)
    - Passes and Transportation, 1909-04 - 1910-01 (Box-folder 336/5)
    - Passes and Transportation, 1910-02 - 1910-11 (Box-folder 336/6)
    - Requests for Plans, 1909-06 - 1910-10 (Box-folder 337/1)
    - Status of Work, 1909-08 - 1910-04 (Box-folder 337/2)
    - Record of Piling, 1911 - 1912 (Box-folder 337/3)
    - Material Requests, 1909-06 - 1910-02 (Box-folder 337/4)
    - Supplies, 1909 (Box-folder 337/5)
    - Supplies, 1910 (Box-folder 337/6)
    - Surveys West, 1909-12 - 1910-08 (Box-folder 337/7)
    - Stations: Savage, Crane, Intake, Sidney, Burns, and Stipek (Montana), 1909-05 - 1910-12 (Box-folder 337/8)
    - Personnel, 1909-06 - 1910-12 (Box-folder 337/9)
    - Telephone and Telegraph, 1910-03 - 1910-07 (Box-folder 337/10)
    - Circular Letters, 1909-08 - 1910-12 (Box-folder 337/11)
    - Coal Used by Contractors, 1909-08 - 1910-02 (Box-folder 337/12)
    - Location Matters, 1909-04 - 1909-11 (Box-folder 338/1)
    - Inventory of Intruments, 1909-05, 1909-09 - 1910-11 (Box-folder 338/2)
    - Channel Change, 1909-08 - 1910-03 (Box-folder 338/3)
    - Government Irrigation, Drainage, and High Water, 1909-06 - 1910-12 (Box-folder 338/4)
    - Insurance for Glendive Material Yard, 1910-06 - 1910-12 (Box-folder 338/5)
    - Soundings and Gasoline Launches, 1909 - 1910 (Box-folder 339/1)
    - Reports on Work, 1910 (Box-folder 339/2)
    - Bates and Rogers Construction, 1909 (Box-folder 339/3)
    - Bates and Rogers Construction, 1910-01 - 1910-03 (Box-folder 339/4)
    - Bates and Rogers Construction, 1910-03 - 1910-12 (Box-folder 339/5)
    - Estimates of Work, Bates and Rogers, 1909-12 - 1910-11 (Box-folder 340/1)
    - Estimates of Work, Pittsburgh Construction, 1911-07 - 1911-11 (Box-folder 340/2)
    - Estimates of Work, Roberts Brothers, 1911-09 - 1912-08 (Box-folder 340/3)
    - Return of Time, 1909-07 - 1911-10 (Box-folder 340/4)
    - Return of Time, 1911-11 - 1912-02 (Box-folder 340/5)
    - Return of Time, 1912-03 - 1912-05 (Box-folder 340/6)
    - Return of Time, 1912-06 - 1912-08 (Box-folder 340/7)
    - Expenses, Camps, 1909-06 - 1911-06 (Box-folder 340/8)
    - Expenses, Transportation, 1909-06 - 1909-12 (Box-folder 341/1)
    - Expenses, 1909-06 - 1909-12 (Box-folder 341/2)
    - Expenses, 1910-01 - 1910-02 (Box-folder 341/3)
    - Expenses, 1910-03 - 1910-04 (Box-folder 341/4)
    - Expenses, 1910-05 - 1910-06 (Box-folder 341/5)
    - Expenses, 1910-07 - 1910-09 (Box-folder 341/6)
    - Expenses, Yellowstone Bridge, 1910-10 - 1911-02 and 1911-08 - 1911-12 (Box-folder 341/7)
    - General Financial Records, 1911-12 - 1912-10 (Box-folder 342/1)
    - Disbursements of Expenses, 1909-04 - 1910-03 (Box-folder 342/2)
    - Estimates, Kerrick Construction, 1912 (Box-folder 342/3)
    - Estimates, Wren and Greenough, 1910-01 - 1910-11 (Box-folder 342/4)
    - Estimates, undated (Box-folder 343/1)
    - Force Accounts, 1909 (Box-folder 343/2)
    - Force Account, 1910 (Box-folder 343/3)
    - Force Account, Yellowstone River Bridge, 1909 - 1910 (Box-folder 343/4)
    - Rights of Way Land Transactions, 1909 - 1910 (Box-folder 343/5)
    - Estimates of Work, Yellowstone River Bridge, 1909 - 1910 (Box-folder 343/6)
    - Estimates, Wren and Greenough, 1909 (Box-folder 343/7)
    - Work Train, 1911-09 - 1911-12 (Box-folder 343/8)
    - Work Train, 1912-01 (Box-folder 343/9)
    - Work Train, 1912-02 (Box-folder 344/1)
    - Work Train, 1912-03 and 1912-05 (Box-folder 344/2)
    - Work Train, 1912-06 (Box-folder 344/3)
    - Record of Freight, 1909-07 - 1910-06 (Box-folder 344/4)
    - Construction Progress, 1909 (Box-folder 344/5)
    - Statements of Bridges and Culverts Constructed, undated (Box-folder 344/6)
    - Yardage Statements, 1910 (Box-folder 344/7)
    - Blue Prints of Rights of Way, 1909 (Box-folder 344/8)
    - Expenses, 1909-01 - 1909-08 (Box-folder 345/1)
    - Expenses, 1909-09 - 1910-04 (Box-folder 345/2)
    - Expenses, 1911-02 - 1911-08 (Box-folder 345/3)
    - Expenses, 1911-09 - 1911-12 (Box-folder 345/4)
    - Expenses, 1912-01 - 1912-08 (Box-folder 345/5)
    - Work Done at Berthold Reservation, 1910-04 - 1910-05 (Box-folder 345/6)
    - Statements of Work Done, 1909-06 - 1910-03 (Box-folder 345/7)
    - Material Yard Shipments to Pingree, North Dakota, 1911-07 - 1911-08 (Box-folder 346/1)
    - Employment, 1910 (Box-folder 346/2)
    - Various Extensions, Turtle Lake and Elbowoods, North Dakota, 1909-05 - 1909-08 (Box-folder 346/3)
    - Various Extensions, Turtle Lake and Elbowoods, North Dakota, 1909-09 - 1910-01 (Box-folder 346/4)
    - Various Extensions, Turtle Lake and Elbowoods, North Dakota, 1910-04 - 1910-06 (Box-folder 346/5)
    - Various Extensions, Turtle Lake and Elbowoods, North Dakota, 1910-06 - 1910-07 (Box-folder 346/6)
    - Rights of Way, 1909-05 - 1909-06 (Box-folder 346/7)
    - Rights of Way, 1909-07 - 1910-04 (Box-folder 346/8)
    - General Correspondence, 1909-05 - 1910-11 (Box-folder 347/1)
    - Passes to Various lines, 1909-08 - 1911-02 (Box-folder 347/2)
    - Statements of Work, 1909-09 - 1910-02 (Box-folder 347/3)
    - Estimates of Work, 1909-05 - 1909-09 (Box-folder 347/4)
    - Estimates of Work, 1909-10 - 1909-11 (Box-folder 347/5)
    - Estimates of Work, 1909-12 - 1910-01 (Box-folder 347/6)
    - Estimates of Work, 1910-04 - 1910-09 (Box-folder 348/1)
    - Expenses Accompanying Estimates of Work, 1909-05 - 1910-02 (Box-folder 348/2)
    - Expenses Accoumpanying Estimates of Work, 1910-04 - 1910-10 (Box-folder 348/3)
    - Return of Time, 1909-06 - 1909-12, 1910-05, 1910-07, and 1910-08 (Box-folder 348/4)
    - Return of Time, ElbowoodsWest, North Dakota, 1910-04 - 1910-07 (Box-folder 348/5)
    - Inventory of Instruments and Camp Supplies, 1909-05 - 1909-12 and 1912-04 (Box-folder 348/6)
    - Sketches of Additional Rights of Way, undated (Box-folder 348/7)
    - Estimates of Work, 1910-02 - 1910-11 (Box-folder 348/8)
    - Expenses Accompanying Estimates of Work, 1910-02 - 1910-12 (Box-folder 348/9)
  - Northern Pacific and Montana Railway Company, 1883-1908; Series XLII; 2.0 linear feet
    The Northern Pacific and Montana Railway Company main lines ran from Logan to Butte, Montana and from De Smet, Montana to the Idaho state line. There were also numerous branch lines. This series contains general construction correspondence, newspaper clippings, maps and construction drawings, work force reports, and general financial ledgers.
    - General Correspondence, 1890-01-22 - 1890-05-09 (Box-folder 349/1)
    - General Correspondence, 1890-05-10 - 1890-05-19 (Box-folder 349/2)
    - General Correspondence, 1890-05-20 - 1890-05-26 (Box-folder 349/3)
    - General Correspondence, 1890-05-27 - 1890-06-05 (Box-folder 349/4)
    - General Correspondence, 1890-06-06 - 1890-06-12 (Box-folder 349/5)
    - General Correspondence, 1890-06-13 - 1890-06-21 (Box-folder 349/6)
    - General Correspondence, 1890-06-22 - 1890-06-28 (Box-folder 349/7)
    - General Correspondence, 1890-06-29 - 1890-08-05 (Box-folder 349/8)
    - General Correspondence, 1890-08-06 - 1890-08-18 (Box-folder 349/9)
    - General Correspondence, 1890-08-19 - 1890-08-29 (Box-folder 349/10)
    - General Correspondence, 1890-08-30 - 1890-09-08 (Box-folder 349/11)
    - General Correspondence, 1890-09-09 - 1890-09-19 (Box-folder 349/12)
    - General Correspondence, 1890-09-20 - 1890-09-30 (Box-folder 350/1)
    - General Correspondence, 1890-10-01 - 1890-10-10 (Box-folder 350/2)
    - General Correspondence, 1890-10-11 - 1890-10-18 (Box-folder 350/3)
    - General Correspondence, 1890-10-19 - 1890-10-26 (Box-folder 350/4)
    - General Correspondence, 1890-10-27- 1891-02-26 (Box-folder 350/5)
    - Clippings, 1890 (Box-folder 350/6)
    - Maps and Drawings, undated (Box-folder 350/7)
    - Outgoing Correspondence, 1898-01 - 1899-09 (Box-volume 350/470)
    - Outgoing Correspondence, 1898-10 - 1899-01 and 1899-07 - 1899-09 (Box-volume 351/471)
    - Outgoing Correspondence, Force Accounts, 1898-10 - 1899-09 (Box-volume 351/472)
    - Outgoing Correspondence, J. C. Bredlove, 1907-07 - 1907-10 (Box-volume 351/473)
    - Outgoing Correspondence, J. C. Bredlove, 1908-07 - 1908-08 (Box-volume 351/474)
    - Outgoing Correspondence, J. C. Bredlove, 1908-10 - 1908-11 (Box-volume 352/475)
    - Journal and Day Book, Butte Quarry, 1883-06 - 1883-11 (Box-volume 352/476)
    - Ledger, Butte Quarry, 1883-06 - 1883-12 (Box-volume 352/477)
    - Bills, Accounts Receivable, 1888-01 - 1892-12 (Box-volume 352/478)
  - Northern Pacific and Puget Sound Shore Railroad Company, 1882-1891; Series XLIII; 1.25 linear feet and 1 oversize volume
    The Northern Pacific and Puget Sound Shore Railroad Company main line operated between Meeker and Seattle, Washington, with branch lines to Kennydale and from Kirkland Junction to Kirkland, Washington. The company was incorporated on August 23, 1884 and was sold to the NPRR on April 21, 1898. This series consists of outgoing construction correspondence, project invoices, construction supply reports, traffic summaries, and personnel records.
    - Outgoing Correspondence, G. H. Pratt, 1890-01 - 1891-06 (Box-volume 353/479)
    - Outgoing Correspondence, 1890-10 - 1891-03 (Box-volume 353/480)
    - Outgoing Correspondence, H.C. Estep, 1891-07 - 1891-09 (Box-volume 353/481)
    - Activity Ledger, 1882-10 - 1883-08 (Box-volume 353/482)
    - Invoice Record, 1890-06 - 1891-04 (Box-volume 353/483)
    - Invoice Record, 1890-08 - 1891-07 (Box-volume 354/484)
    - Invoice Record, 1891-04 - 1891-09 (Box-volume 354/485)
    - Expense Bills, 1890 - 1891 (Box-volume 354/486)
    - Material Distribution Record, 1890 (Box-volume 354/487)
    - Material Received, 1890-06 - 1891-01 (Box-volume 354/488)
    - Materials Received, 1890-09 - 1891-09 (Box-volume 354/489)
    - Materials Received, 1891-04 - 1891-09 (Volume 490)
    - Time Reports and Trainmen, 1900-10 - 1901-01 (Box-volume 354/491)
    - Requisitions for Material and Supplies, 1890-08 - 1891-08 (Box-volume 355/492)
    - Car Reports, 1890-10 - 1891-08 (Box-volume 355/493)
    - Car Reports and Material on Hand, 1891-02 - 1891-08 (Box-volume 355/494)
  - Peninsular Branch (Washington), 1901-1906; Series XLIV; 1.25 linear feet
    The Peninsular Branch operated between Shelton and Gordonville, Washington. This series consists of construction correspondence, supply records, subcontracted projects, facility locations and designs, line repair projects, traffic summaries, progress reports, personnel documents, and operational expense records.
    - General Correspondence, 1904-04 - 1904-07 (Box-folder 356/1)
    - General Correspondence, 1904-08 (Box-folder 356/2)
    - General Correspondence, 1904-09 (Box-folder 356/3)
    - General Correspondence, 1904-10 (Box-folder 356/4)
    - General Correspondence, 1904-11 (Box-folder 356/5)
    - General Correspondence, 1904-12 (Box-folder 357/1)
    - General Correspondence, 1905-01 - 1906-01 (Box-folder 357/2)
    - Bids and Proposals, 1901-03 - 1902-03 (Box-folder 357/3)
    - Stations, 1901-08 - 1902-01 (Box-folder 357/4)
    - Location of Line, 1901-12 - 1902-01 (Box-folder 357/5)
    - Grading and Washouts, 1901-10 - 1904-03 (Box-folder 357/6)
    - Contracts, 1901-06 - 1904-05 (Box-folder 357/7)
    - Requisitions, 1901-06 - 1905-03 (Box-folder 357/8)
    - Supply Materials, 1901-06 - 1905-03 (Box-folder 357/9)
    - Bridges, 1901-07 - 1903-03 (Box-folder 357/10)
    - Car Reports, 1901-07 - 1901-12 (Box-folder 357/11)
    - Track Laying, 1901-07 - 1904-05 (Box-folder 357/12)
    - Fencing, 1901-08 (Box-folder 357/13)
    - Estimates, 1901-08 - 1903-01 (Box-folder 357/14)
    - Progress of Work, 1901-07 - 1905-05 (Box-folder 357/15)
    - Expense Account, C.C. Van Arsdol, 1901-08 - 1902-01 (Box-folder 357/16)
    - Graders, 1901-07 - 1901-12 (Box-folder 357/17)
    - Inspection of Ties, 1901-07 - 1901-08 (Box-folder 357/18)
    - Cribbing, 1901-07 - 1902-03 (Box-folder 357/19)
    - Passes, 1901-12 - 1902-03 (Box-folder 357/20)
    - Employment Agents, 1901-12 - 1902-01 (Box-folder 357/21)
    - Employees, 1901-06 - 1901-12 (Box-folder 357/22)
    - Operation of Line, 1902-01 (Box-folder 357/23)
    - Outgoing Correspondence, 1901-07 - 1902-04 (Box-volume 358/495)
  - Port Townsend and Southern Railroad, 1906-1907; Series XLV; 1 bound volume
    The Port Townsend and Southern Railroad operated main lines between Tenino and Olympia and between Port Townsend and Quilcene, Washington. The main line was sold to the NPRR in 1914; the line was then sold to Joshua Green in 1917. This series consist of one bound volume of purchase vouchers.
    - Vouchers, 1906-07 - 1907-04 (Box-volume 358/496)
  - Puget Sound Shore Railroad, 1891; Series XLVI; 1 bound volume
    The Puget Sound Shore Railroad operated a line between Stuck Junction (south of Kent) to Seattle, Washington. The company was incorporated on August 19, 1882 and was sold to the Northern Pacific and Puget Sound Shore Railroad Company October 31, 1889; which was in turn sold to the NPRR on April 21, 1898. This series contains one bound volume of outgoing correspondence from H. C. Estep, Assistant Engineer.
    - Outgoing Correspondence, H. C. Estep, 1891-03 - 1891-07 (Box-volume 358/497)
  - Rocky Fork and Cooke City Railway Company, 1889-1890; XLVII; 0.5 linear feet
    The Rocky Fork and Cooke City Railway Company operated a line from Laurel to Red Lodge, Montana. The company was incorporated on December 10, 1886 and merged into the NPRR on April 21, 1898. This series consists of four bound outgoing correspondence volumes from Chief Engineer A. J. Merritt, one station ledger, and an supplies order book.
    - Outgoing Correspondence, A. J. Merritt, 1889-05 - 1889-11 (Box-volume 359/498)